import { Flashcard } from "../types";

export const basicSpanish: Flashcard[] = [
    // Colors
    {front: "Blue", back: "Azul"},
    {front: "Yellow", back: "Amarillo"},
    {front: "Red", back: "Rojo"},
    {front: "Pink", back: "Rosa"},
    {front: "Orange", back: "Azul"},
    {front: "Green", back: "Verde"},
    {front: "Violet", back: "Violeta"},
    {front: "Purple", back: "Morado"},
    {front: "Brown", back: "Marrón"},
    {front: "Black", back: "Negro"},
    {front: "White", back: "Blanco"},
    {front: "Gray", back: "Gris"},
    {front: "Silver", back: "Azul"},
    {front: "Gold", back: "Azul"},
    {front: "Khaki", back: "Azul"},
    
    // Directions
    {front: "Right", back: "Derecha"},
    {front: "Left", back: "Izquierda"},
    {front: "Ahead", back: "Adelante"},
    {front: "Behind", back: "Altras"},
    {front: "In Front", back: "En Frente"},
    {front: "Far", back: "Lejos"},
    {front: "Close", back: "Cerca"},
    {front: "Next To", back: "Al Lado"},
    {front: "At", back: "En"},
    {front: "Inside", back: "Adentra"},
    {front: "Outside", back: "Afuera"},
    {front: "From", back: "Desde"},

    // Greetings
    {front: "Hello", back: "Hola"},
    {front: "Goodbye", back: "Adios"},
    {front: "Good Morning", back: "Buenos Dias"},
    {front: "Good Afternoon", back: "Buenas Tardes"},
    {front: "Good Evening", back: "Buenas Noches"},
    {front: "Thank you", back: "Gracias"},
    {front: "Please", back: "Por favor"},
    {front: "Excuse me", back: "Perdon"},
    {front: "I'm sorry", back: "Lo siento"},

    // Answers
    {front: "Yes", back: "Si"},
    {front: "No", back: "No"},
    {front: "Maybe", back: "Tal Vez"},
    {front: "I'm not sure", back: "No estoy seguro"},

    // Pronouns
    {front: "I", back: "Yo"},
    {front: "You", back: "Tu"},
    {front: "He", back: "El"},
    {front: "She", back: "Ella"},
    {front: "It", back: "El"},
    {front: "We", back: "Nosotros"},
    {front: "They", back: "Ellos"},

    // Days of the week
    {front: "Monday", back: "Lunes"},
    {front: "Tuesday", back: "Martes"},
    {front: "Wednesday", back: "Miercoles"},
    {front: "Thursday", back: "Jueves"},
    {front: "Friday", back: "Viernes"},
    {front: "Saturday", back: "Sabado"},
    {front: "Sunday", back: "Domingo"},

    //Months of the year
    {front: "January", back: "Enero"},
    {front: "February", back: "Febrero"},
    {front: "March", back: "Marzo"},
    {front: "April", back: "Abril"},
    {front: "May", back: "Mayo"},
    {front: "June", back: "Junio"},
    {front: "July", back: "Julio"},
    {front: "August", back: "Agosto"},
    {front: "September", back: "Septiembre"},
    {front: "October", back: "Octubre"},
    {front: "November", back: "Noviembre"},
    {front: "December", back: "Diciembre"},

    //Animals
    {front: "Bird", back: "Pajaro"},
    {front: "Bull", back: "Toro"},
    {front: "Cat", back: "Gato"},
    {front: "Chicken", back: "Pollo"},
    {front: "Cow", back: "Vaca"},
    {front: "Dog", back: "Perro"},
    {front: "Donkey", back: "Burro"},
    {front: "Duck", back: "Pato"},
    {front: "Fish", back: "Pez"},
    {front: "Goat", back: "Cabra"},
    {front: "Hen", back: "Gallina"},
    {front: "Horse", back: "Caballo"},
    {front: "Pig", back: "Cerdo"},
    {front: "Rabbit", back: "Conejo"},
    {front: "Rooster", back: "Gallo"},
    {front: "Sheep", back: "Oveja"},
    {front: "Turtle", back: "Tortuga"},

    // Family
    {front: "Father", back: "Padre"},
    {front: "Mother", back: "Madre"},
    {front: "Brother", back: "Hermano"},
    {front: "Sister", back: "Hermana"},
    {front: "Grandfather", back: "Abuelo"},
    {front: "Grandmother", back: "Abuela"},
    {front: "Uncle", back: "Tio"},
    {front: "Aunt", back: "Tia"},
    {front: "Nephew", back: "Sobrino"},
    {front: "Niece", back: "Sobrina"},
    {front: "Cousin", back: "Primo"},
    {front: "Grandson", back: "Nieto"},
    {front: "Granddaughter", back: "Nieta"},
    {front: "Son", back: "Hijo"},
    {front: "Daughter", back: "Hija"},
    {front: "Wife", back: "Esposa"},
    {front: "Husband", back: "Esposo"},

    // Actions
    {front: "Go", back: "Ir"},
    {front: "Come", back: "Ven"},
    {front: "Leave", back: "Irse"},
    {front: "Stay", back: "Quedarse"},
    {front: "Sleep", back: "Dormir"},
    {front: "Wake up", back: "Despertar"},
    {front: "Eat", back: "Comer"},
    {front: "Drink", back: "Beber"},
    {front: "Read", back: "Leer"},
    {front: "Write", back: "Escribir"},
    {front: "Listen", back: "Escuchar"},
    {front: "Speak", back: "Hablar"},
    {front: "Think", back: "Pensar"},
    {front: "Feel", back: "Sentir"},
    {front: "Smile", back: "Sonreir"},
    {front: "Cry", back: "Llorar"},
    {front: "Laugh", back: "Reir"},

    // Feelings
    {front: "Happy", back: "Feliz"},
    {front: "Sad", back: "Triste"},
    {front: "Angry", back: "Enojado"},
    {front: "Stressed", back: "Estresado"},
    {front: "Anxious", back: "Ansioso"},
    {front: "Tired", back: "Cansado"},
    {front: "Excited", back: "Emocionado"},

    // Numbers
    {front: "One", back: "Uno"},
    {front: "Two", back: "Dos"},
    {front: "Three", back: "Tres"},
    {front: "Four", back: "Cuatro"},
    {front: "Five", back: "Cinco"},
    {front: "Six", back: "Seis"},
    {front: "Seven", back: "Siete"},
    {front: "Eight", back: "Ocho"},
    {front: "Nine", back: "Nueve"},
    {front: "Ten", back: "Diez"},
    {front: "Eleven", back: "Once"},
    {front: "Twelve", back: "Doce"},
    {front: "Thirteen", back: "Trece"},
    {front: "Fourteen", back: "Catorce"},
    {front: "Fifteen", back: "Quince"},
    {front: "Sixteen", back: "Dieciséis"},
    {front: "Seventeen", back: "Diecisiete"},
    {front: "Eighteen", back: "Dieciocho"},
    {front: "Nineteen", back: "Diecinueve"},
    {front: "Twenty", back: "Veinte"},
    {front: "Thirty", back: "Treinta"},
    {front: "Forty", back: "Cuarenta"},
    {front: "Fifty", back: "Cincuenta"},
    {front: "Sixty", back: "Sesenta"},
    {front: "Seventy", back: "Setenta"},
    {front: "Eighty", back: "Ochenta"},
    {front: "Ninety", back: "Noventa"},
    {front: "One Hundred", back: "Cien"},
    {front: "One Thousand", back: "Mil"},
    {front: "One Million", back: "Millón"},
    {front: "One Billion", back: "Billon"},
    {front: "One Trillion", back: "Trillon"},
];

